Oh no.
Oo.
Oh. Oh, [music]
I feel
Heat. Heat.
Oo.
Oh.
Hey. Hey.
Heat. Heat. N.
Heat. Heat.
Well, thank you for coming to Movement
Church. We hope you had a wonderful time
celebrating America. Are you ready to
celebrate the Lord this morning? Here we
go. Come on.
[music]
Jesus [singing] is mine.
Oh, what a foraste [singing]
of glory [music] divine.
Hear [singing] of salvation,
purchased of [music] God,
born of his spirit. [singing] Oh, I'm
washed in his blood. Oh, [music]
said I can't stop singing. Oh, [singing]
spirit of soul. [music]
I'm praising my savior all the day. for
the table. [music]
I got a song and I'll sing it [singing]
loud. My praise is pouring out. My
[music] praise is pouring out. And I
will dance in your freedom. Now you have
brought me out. You have brought me out.
[music]
Every
[singing]
Jesus is mine.
Oh, what [singing] a full taste
of glory [music] divine.
>> Of salvation.
>> Of [singing] salvation.
Purchase [music] of God of his spirit,
born of his [singing] spirit. Oh, I'm
watching his love. Oh, [music]
I can't stop singing.
[music]
[singing]
I'm praising my savior. [music] All day
long, all day long. I got a song and
sing it out. Heat. Heat.
[music]
You brought me out. I got a song.
[singing]
[music]
I got a song.
[singing]
My
[music]
greatest.
[music and singing]
[music]
Oh, thank you, Lord. We're free. Amen.
God, if you're free, let's sing. Hey,
here we go. Hey. Hey.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
We thank you, Jesus.
From the sunset free. [music]
Oh, we thank you. [music]
We thank [singing] you, Lord, for your
word. [music]
Hey,
[music]
your [singing] word
is a lamp unto [music] my feet.
And your way
is the [music] only [singing] way for
me.
It's a narrow road, [singing and music]
but the mercies are wide. Cuz you're
good on your promise.
Oh, it's a narrow [singing]
road, [music] but then we'll lead life.
But I want to be honest,
and I'll [singing] take you at your
[music] word.
Said [singing] it out.
See how good it was. [music]
finding [singing] your
I take you as [music and singing]
oh
[music]
you know
the chaos will [music]
I know
[singing] it in my
Narrow road that leads
[music and singing] to life. We don't
want to be on it.
Narrow road the tide is high to [music]
part in the water.
I want to [singing] take you as
said [music and singing]
I believe.
I see how [singing] good you are.
[music]
I'll take [music] you as
it [music and singing]
see.
[singing and music]
I'll take you. [music and singing]
[music]
I'll take you.
All your promises are [music]
[singing]
your love will never [music and singing]
give up. You say your grace is always
enough. You say your heart will never
[music and singing] forget or forsake
me. Oh,
you said I'm safe. You call me [music]
yours. You said my future full of your
[music and singing] fail. So I know that
you'll never fail me.
[music]
You said your [singing] love never give
up. You said [music] your race is always
enough. You said your
[music and singing] heart never forget
for me.
[music]
You said [singing]
you
[music]
said my future
and you never [music and singing]
so I know that you'll never
[music]
[singing]
[music] if you said it [singing] I'll
leave it. I've seen [music] how good it
was. Yes, I have.
>> [singing]
[music]
>> I'll take you out.
[singing and music]
[singing]
[music]
Heat.
Heat. [singing]
[music]
[singing]
>> [music]
>> I will take you [music and singing] by
the Lord praise. [music] Oh, we thank
you, Jesus.
Oh, we bless your name,
[music and singing] Jesus.
Come on, church. Let's just lift our
hands and thank the Lord this morning
for his goodness, for his promises.
[music]
Oh, we thank you Lord.
Oh, we thank you for your promisees.
[singing]
Because it is written, [music]
you're my [singing] refuge and strength.
Though the earth may pass [music] away,
will remain.
And it [music and singing] is written
that you provide every [singing]
need
everywhere [music] that you will lead.
You will sustain.
You keep [music and singing]
your promises.
[music and singing] Your goodness
never
ends. [music]
From [singing] generation
to generation [music and singing]
you keep your covenant.
[music]
See your faithfulness. [singing]
>> You see your faithfulness
>> from [singing] generation.
>> From generation [music]
to generation. [singing]
[singing]
For it is written, [music]
we're redeemed by [singing] your blood.
All the old has passed away.
[music and singing] The new has come.
For it is written, [singing]
it's now by power
by spirit [music and singing]
of the living.
Oh, [music and singing] you keep your
promises
for [music and singing] your goodness.
generation
[music and singing] generation
to generation.
[music and singing]
[singing and music]
>> [music and singing]
>> Oh,
we thank you Lord.
You are faithful God.
Oh, we [music and singing] thank you,
Lord. Come on, let's thank you for his
faithfulness. Oh, we thank you. We will
trust [singing] you and [music] believe
as it's rich and let it be. You alone
will be a firm [music and singing]
foundation.
Lord, what you spoken is enough.
[music and singing] And it's the crown
we're standing on. You are kind
[singing]
and we will [music] not be shen.
Oh, we [music and singing] will trust
you and believe. And as it's written,
let it be. [music] Cuz you alone
[singing] will be a
[music]
strong
[singing]
[music]
[music and singing]
[singing]
Heat. Heat. Heat.
[music]
[singing]
Yeah.
Heat. [music]
[singing]
[music]
Heat. Heat. Heat.
[music and singing]
Heat.
[music]
[singing]
>> [music]
>> You are you
[singing and music]
Jesus.
Oh, we thank you, Lord. [singing]
We thank Oh, we thank you, Lord. Come
[music] on, lift your hands and
[singing] thank the Lord this morning.
Oh, we thank [music and singing] you
Jesus.
Oh,
we thank [singing]
you Jesus. [music]
Oh, [singing]
we [music] thank you Jesus.
Come on, thank him this [music] morning
for his promises. They are yes and
[singing] amen. His word is final
authority. So we thank you for that,
Father. We [music] thank you [singing]
Lord. We thank you Lord.
>> Oh we thank you Lord. We [singing] thank
you [music] Lord.
>> Oh come on. We thank you Jesus.
[singing]
[music]
>> We thank you Lord. You're so faithful
[singing]
God.
>> You're so faithful
Lord. [music]
>> From generations.
>> Oh [singing] we bless you Lord
>> to generations. We bless you, [music]
Lord. [singing]
We bless you, Jesus.
He's such a faithful God.
[music]
Oh, we worship you, Lord.
We bless [music and singing]
your name.
And I'm going to [singing] hit it
[music]
with the last name.
All [singing] the saints and angels
[music]
they bow [singing] before
your [music] throne.
>> [singing]
>> All the elders [music]
cast their crowns before [singing] the
lamb
of God [music]
and [singing] sing all the saints.
All [music] the saints and [singing]
angels [music]
that bow before [singing]
your throne.
>> [singing and music]
>> All the elders
cast their crowns [singing] before the
lamb
of God and sing. [music]
You are worthy [singing] of it all.
Lord, [music and singing] you're worthy
of it all.
For [singing and music] from you are all
things and to you are all you deserve.
>> You deserve the [music and singing]
glory.
All the saints and angels
we sing [music and singing] all the
saint and angels
they bow [singing and music] before
your throne.
Oh,
all [singing] the [music]
elders
cast their crowns before the lamb
[music]
of God
and [singing]
sing. Lord, you're worthy [music] of it
all.
He's worthy. Yes, he is, Lord. [music]
You are worthy [singing]
of it all.
Yes, you are. [music]
[singing]
from you are
[singing] you
[music]
deserve
glory
[singing]
[music] you
[singing] see [music]
[singing]
you Heat. Heat. Heat. [music]
[music]
Yeah.
Heat. [music]
[singing]
[music and singing]
Heat. [music]
Heat.
[music]
[singing]
you
are [music] so clear right now. We lift
our hands, we lift our voices, and we
worship you, Jesus. [music]
Oh, there's a night like you, Lord.
There's a man like you, Lord.
[music and singing]
Oh, we [music and singing] bless your
name. We bless your name.
Oh,
[music]
[singing]
and we sing day and [music and singing]
night, night and day, their worship for
us.
[music] Day and night, [singing]
night and day, their worship.
Day and night. [music]
Sing it out. We sing day and night.
Heat. Heat. [music and singing]
[singing]
Heat. [music]
Heat. [singing]
[music and singing]
Yeah.
Heat. [music]
[music and singing]
[music]
[singing]
Oh,
[music] you
[singing]
[music]
Heat. [singing]
Heat.
[music and singing]
Yeah.
Heat.
[music]
[singing]
Yeah. [music]
Heat.
[music]
Oh,
[singing]
[music]
Jesus.
I
[music]
exalt [singing] thee. Exalt the Lord.
You are highly [music] exalt.
[singing]
>> I exalt.
>> Come on. Let's lift that up this [music]
morning. Lord, [singing]
>> I exalt
thee. Oh. [music]
>> Oh,
[singing]
we your name. We exalt you Jesus name.
[music]
>> I [singing]
exalt
thee.
>> Oh exalt you Jesus.
>> I [singing]
exalt [music]
thee
>> over everything. Lord I [singing]
exalt
thee. [music]
>> Oh [singing]
[music]
cuz you're worthy of it all.
Lord, you're [music and singing] worthy
of it all.
We tell him this morning, you're worthy.
You're worthy of it all.
[music and singing]
>> For from [music and singing] you are all
things and to you are all things.
>> You deserve
>> You deserve the glory.
[music and singing]
You're worthy of it all. Lord,
>> you are worthy [singing] of [music] it
all.
>> So worthy, Jes.
>> You are worthy of it all. [music]
>> So worthy [singing] of our praise.
For from you are all things. [singing]
And to [music] you,
>> from you,
far from you [singing] are all things.
And [music] to you are all [singing]
for from you are all [music] things and
to you are all things.
You [music and singing] deserve the
glory.
[singing]
[music]
We
[singing]
[music]
bless your name. We bless.
>> We bless your [singing] name. We bless.
[music]
>> Oh, we worship you, Jesus.
[singing]
[music]
>> Lord, we praise you.
>> We praise you.
>> Worthy of it all. All glory is yours,
Lord. [music] You are so worthy. Thank
you Lord every day for this amazing
country [music] you put us in. Thank you
Lord for giving us a place where we can
freely worship you, where we can put you
in your rightful place above all things
because you are the only [music] one one
worthy to be put above all things. Thank
you God. You know when I was praying on
what God wanted me to talk about during
this moment, he led me to Isaiah 53. And
if you don't know that chapter, it's all
about a coming Messiah and what he was
going to have to suffer with. He was
going to be pierced for our
transgressions. He was going to be
crushed for our iniquities. He was going
to die for our sins. It's talking about
Jesus. It's all [music] about Jesus. And
you know, I was thinking, what what is
it about this specific chapter that he
wants me to talk about? We know about
Jesus's love and how he died for us, how
he gave himself up for us. But the last
verse in that chapter [music] is what
hit me. The last one is talking about
how he makes intercessions for the
transgressors. That was us. We were the
ones [music] transgressing against him.
And so he makes intercessions for us.
But what does that mean? Intercessions
is kind of a big silly word that a lot
of us don't really use. But if you look
at the Greek translation when that old
[music] testament was translated to the
new the Greek that word is what we would
kind of use for like a defense lawyer.
The Greeks are big on law. And so the
transgressor is saying that Jesus or I
mean intercession is saying that Jesus
is going to speak on your behalf. He's
gonna speak to God and be like, "You
know what? This man has made mistakes,
but don't worry [music] about that. He's
a good man." You know why? Because he
points to his side. He shows you his
hands because his sin was already paid
for. So the opposite side of that is the
accuser. So we all know the accuser.
That's the enemy. And that is what we
would use for the word persecutor or
prosecutor in our legalistic mindset.
So, he, the enemy, is trying to accuse
us of all of these things. He's trying
to say, "You know what? You didn't do
this right. You didn't do that right.
God, look at him. Look at him. He made
mistakes. You should send him to the
fiery lake. You should punish him. You
should let me torment him." And Jesus is
like, "You know what? Bought and paid
for. Bought and paid for. I died for
that man. So, his sins, everything he's
doing, it it doesn't matter anymore.
Now, he doesn't need to do that anymore.
He should stop doing these things and
follow me. But I [music] paid for it, so
it doesn't matter anymore. Don't even
look at him, Lord. Look at me. So that's
what Jesus is doing for us after he died
on that cross. He bought and paid for
all of our sins [music] so that we don't
have to suffer the what the accuser
thinks we need to suffer.
>> So right now, maybe something's being
put on your heart that you made a
mistake. That's the accuser. He's trying
to get into your mind and tell you that
you didn't do this right. You didn't do
that right. Remember, you have the
perfect defense attorney. And he's free.
>> He's free. He's not going to cost you a
dime.
He fought and paid for it. So, you don't
have to live that life. So, maybe right
now you're at home with a stomach bug.
And the accuser is hitting you in your
mind. You should be at church right now.
Don't worry about it. Jesus got you.
>> He's taking care of you. Don't listen to
that accuser. You're listening right
now. We see you. We know you're here.
So you don't have to suffer that pain,
that torment, that anguish that that
accuser is trying to bring on your life
because you have the best defense
attorney that already bought and paid
for any crime you may have made, making
or will make in the future, it is gone
in Jesus name. So I thank you, Father,
every day that you sent your son to die
for our sins, to wash us clean in his
blood, to cover us with [music] his
love,
to protect us, to speak on our behalf,
to just be everything we could possibly
need. We love you so much, Lord. We
thank you every day in Jesus name. Amen.
>> Amen.
>> You be seated.
Oh, happy birthday.
Happy America birthday. As my wife likes
to say, happy 250.
250. It's crazy. Oh, man. This is a been
a very interesting time. You know, we
have this every year, Fourth of July,
but this is a big one. This is
different.
It's not because we had a UFC fight at
the White House. It's not because we had
some silly things happen. It feels like
there's a tide turning that people are
starting to wake up to see that this is
really the greatest country that exists
today and I think has ever existed
before. No country has been as free as
us. Now we have had mistakes. We have
made you know mistakes in the past and
have a dark past but every country has
made mistakes. We were the first country
to start to correct these mistakes to,
you know, I I heard something recently
that the northern [music] colonies, even
before England signed a proclamation
freeing slaves, the northern colonies of
this United States of America had
already put it in their state
constitutions that slavery should be
abandoned, should be abolished. So, we
did it before England did it. And
England usually gets the the notoriety
for being the ones that abolish slavery
first. Well, actually, a lot of the
states in America did it first. We
weren't perfect, and it took some of us
a little bit longer to get there, but
you know, every state, every country at
the time had slavery. You can't take our
past mistakes and hold it to us against
us in the future because this country
[music] allows so much freedom. We have
so much more freedom and so much more,
you know, [music] rights for everybody,
for women, for uh for all races, all
genders. You know, there's only two, but
both of them have equal equal rights.
And so I I'm so grateful for this nation
and just you look at all the Europeans
coming over here for the FIFA World Cup
and what they're they're saying is
America is amazing. These people are so
nice. The food is great. You know, all
these amazing things. is a beautiful
place, not like what the media tells us.
We've all thought this place is a bunch
of horrible, mean people, but that's not
what this country is. That's not what it
was founded to be, and it's not what it
is now.
>> And so, we have to stop listening to the
noise and just open your eyes to what
you see. And right now, I see just a
room filled with all different kinds of
people. people that are great, people
that are loved by Jesus that are not
really any different from one another.
And it is amazing melting pot of what
this country really is. And so on this
250 birthday, I wasn't planning on
talking about this. The Holy Spirit just
was bringing it out of me. You know, I I
just encourage you to stop listening to
the garbage that's trying to tear this
down, this country down, tear everybody
apart, rip [music] us into these little
factions. That's not what this country
is made to be. That's not what God wants
us to be because that's not what it's
going to be like in heaven. We're all
going to be just one big loved group of
people that are going to love each
other, love God, and just be in perfect
fellowship. And that's what we need to
be here every day. So, stop listening to
the junk and just listen to Jesus.
>> And so, if this if this is your first
time here, I welcome you. This is an
amazing place that I've had been
privileged to be with from the very
first Bible study at the pastor's house.
And we've come a very long way and we
have a very long way to go. But if this
is your first time here, I welcome you
to get this uh one of these packets up
at the front. It's got a little gift
card in it. It tells you a little bit
more about the church. And really what
the goal here is is why it's called
Movement Church. It's to move you from
where you are into where God has called
you to be. I was broken. I was lost. I
was hurting. And now through Jesus
Christ. I am redeemed. I am whole. I am
so much better than I ever was. And I
thank in part to this church. This is an
amazing church that God is really
working through. So, if this is your
first time here, get the the p the
packet. You can fill out the QR code. Uh
well, you can scan the QR code and it'll
take you to a form that you can fill
out. Just tells us a little bit about
you. Uh, we're not going to hound you or
anything, but um, you know what I really
encourage you to do is come back. Don't
just go come one time. Come back for a
second time, maybe a third time or 40 or
50 times because you'll see the love.
You'll see the power here because this
[music] place is filled with the Holy
Spirit.
>> And it is is amazing place that can
really change lives. So, if you need
something in your life to change, come
back here and you'll find it. I
guarantee it.
So, as you can kind of see, there's a
lot of open chairs here. It's not
normally the case. There's, you know,
the enemy is trying to attack a lot of
the uh members of this church, and we
come against that in the name of Jesus.
But usually, this place is very, very
full. And so, we need to go to the next
step. We were first at the the pastor's
house. That filled up real quick. They
really wanted us to, you know, find
something else. Then we went to uh Mud
Pies and Lullabies which was um a great
little place but we were ready to move
out of that. Now we're here and this
place has been an amazing blessing for
us but it's not our final destination.
So we have another step the next step
that we're going to we're getting land
we're getting a building and with that
you know we are standing in faith
because it's not easy to to just
automatically have that unless you know
somebody here has 20 30 acres of land
that are willing to give. then it's
really easy. Um, praise the Lord. So,
[music] every week we say a confession
about where we're going, about where
we're heading. We're standing in faith
on the word of God, on the promises of
God that he's given our pastors, he's
given this church that there are going
to be amazing things coming from this
church. There already have been, but
[music] we've got so many more amazing
things to come. Just talk to the pastors
for like three minutes and they'll give
you 47 ideas of what they're doing in
the future. starting Bible colleges. You
know, we already started a school here.
It's just there's so much amazing
things. So, I encourage you to say these
confessions with us in faith, boldly,
confidently knowing that this is where
we're heading. It's not just a ritual.
This is a faith statement that we are
putting out there because your words
have power.
>> Amen.
>> So, all grace abounds towards us. We
have everything we need to accomplish
all that God has called us to do. We
thank you Lord for our land and we call
it paid for in Jesus' name. We thank you
Lord for the provision to build all the
buildings needed for Movement Church,
Movement Christian Academy and every
work you call us to do. We say yes to
your plan and we thank you for your
grace to complete our assignment. We
call this done in Jesus name. Amen.
Thank you Lord.
So, if God has put it on your heart that
you want to start providing to that, you
know, through uh tithings, through
offerings, there's a lot of different
ways that you can give. You can scan the
QR code um on the screen. It'll take you
to our app. Or you can uh tap the little
circle um on the back of the chairs that
will also take you to our app. Or
there's an old school offering box in
the back nailed to the wall that you
know, we don't really pass the the
buckets around anymore. Um, but you
know, the the the main thing that God
always puts on my heart is test me in
this area. Test me with your finances. I
always think about this because it's the
one area God tells you to test him on.
And when you test him on it, he is
always faithful to provide. We were not
tithing when we first started. We
actually had the very opposite mindset
of, oh, they just want to take all our
money. But once we started to open our
eyes to, you remember I said broken
moved here. So we were lost and broken,
we we found our way into the, you know,
the right mindset of what God wants to
do with your finances. So when you test
him, when you start to tithe and you
start to provide offerings, he will
always give back. So when we finally
started, it was like the next year, I
think both of us got promotions. Both of
us got out of cycle raises. We were
getting bonuses left and right. Money
was just flowing into us. were like,
"Oh, I don't know what to do with all
this." We didn't have any kids, so it
was pretty awesome at that point. We
took a lot of international vacations.
Um, and we will again soon. Praise the
Lord. But, you know, and we we kept
staying faithful. And I just got a
promotion just this last week. So, the
Lord is good. He will always provide for
you. He will always open up the windows
of heaven and pour out his blessings
onto you. So, I invite you to say
prayers with me in faith that if the
Lord is putting something on your heart
to open that up and provide that to the
Lord through the church through, you
know, it doesn't even always have to be
through the church. You can give in
other ways that show your love to of
Jesus. So, you can show your love to
other people. So, I'm going to say a
prayer over the offerings and I invite
you to say, you know, something else
with me. Say a prayer in your own heart
and your own words [music] that you know
God will open up your mind to the
importance of tithing and providing
offerings. Father God, I thank you so
much every day for how good you are. You
are the only one worthy of our praise,
of our offerings, of our time, of our
tithing, of everything we have. It is
all yours because it was always yours.
And you've just given it to us first
because you loved us. Just like
children, you give us gifts and
blessings just like I give my children
gifts and blessings because I love them.
Your love for us is just so much more so
much more powerful, [music] so much more
generous. And so Lord, I pray that you
just help those around here that are
questioning whether tithing and
offerings are a good thing or the right
thing. You just speak to them. You just
give them knowledge. Give them wisdom.
give them something that shows your love
and what you do with this that it was
all yours to begin with and we're just
giving back in thanks. So I thank you
Lord for everybody here, everyone that's
tithing, everyone that's providing,
everyone that's going to provide in the
future. I pray you open up the windows
of heaven. Pour out just blessing on
blessing on blessing [music] on them so
it's so overwhelming to them that they
can't help but provide more. not just to
the church but to everyone they interact
with. They just be just a beacon of
offering and blessing to others so that
others can see your heart. In Jesus name
we pray. Amen.
[music]
Hey movement parents, we've got some
exciting news for you. The MC kids
parent newsletter is now available on
the movement app. All you have to do is
open the app, tap on movement kids, and
it'll take you directly to the
newsletter. Or if you're here in
service, you can simply tap your phone
to the sticker on the back of your
chair, and it'll bring it up for you
that way. The parent newsletter has
everything you need to keep you
connected and up to date with what your
kids are learning each week. You'll find
an overview of our current series,
details about what we're teaching each
Sunday, including a memory verse video
that has hand motions to go along with
it, and then there are also some simple
ways that you can keep the conversation
going at home throughout the week as you
disciple your kids together as a family.
Also, if you want a copy to save or to
share, then you're able to download that
at the bottom of that screen. So, check
it out today and don't forget to turn on
your app notifications so you never miss
an update or announcement. We're so
excited to continue partnering with you
as your kids grow in their faith.
>> Comment,
>> share,
>> comment,
>> share.
>> Hey, Movement Church family. If you love
what God is doing here, help us share
it. [music] So, I'm going to ask you to
take out your phone. Go ahead. You're
not going to get in trouble. I will
wait.
If you have your phone, go to social
media. I know you have it. to go to
Instagram or Facebook and take a [music]
second to like, comment, or share our
most recent post. Every interaction
helps more people discover Jesus and
experience what is happening here at
Movement Church. Let's not be the best
kept secret here in Theina. Help us
spread the word.
>> [music]
>> Heat. Hey, Heat.
Amen. Praise the Lord. Well, who had a
good time yesterday on the 4th of July?
Anybody blow anything up?
>> Didn't blowing your fingers up, did you?
Everybody got your fingers and your toes
and everything? Well, as Josh mentioned,
we just want to celebrate with you guys
what an amazing country that we live in.
>> 250 years. I mean, think about this.
There's a lot. Think about the other
nations uh and countries on the planet.
And they've been around a long time.
We've only been around 250 years. That's
not very long at all. But look at what
God has done in only 250 years.
>> Don't make no mistake about it. This is
the Lord's work in the United States of
America. The reason the United States of
America is so successful is because we
are one nation under God.
That's why because we chose God. You
there's a uh God chose the nation of
Israel to be his his people. But we as a
people chose God. We as a nation chose
him. That is awesome. And God, you know,
we we share more gospel from the United
States than any other country combined
on the planet. The gospel is being
spread all throughout the world from the
United States of America. Amen. We send
out more missionaries than anybody else.
We send out more financial aid than
anybody else. We send out more food than
anybody else. We are making this planet
great. Amen.
>> Make the planet great again.
Amen. [laughter]
Well, praise God. I got a couple of dad
jokes for you today.
>> Amen. These are good. I'm telling you,
these are really good. See, I asked my
wife the other day, or actually, she
asked me. She said, "Did you see the dog
bowl?" She'd asked me if I've seen the
dog bowl and I said, "No, I didn't know
that he did."
That'll catch on here in just a minute.
My doctor uh I told my doctor that I
broke my arm in two places. He told me
to start avoiding those two places.
[laughter]
And this is the Star Wars one. I got to
throw a Star Wars one every week this
week. It's for the Star Wars group. If
you don't know Star Wars, then you won't
have any idea what I'm talking about.
But what sound do Yoda's sheep make?
They go by.
They go by. See, they laughed really
hard. They go by. Yoda was from Deoba.
>> Anyway, I got it.
>> You got it. Amen. Praise God. Well,
let's talk about something that we can
all relate to. Our covenant.
>> Did you know that you have a covenant
with Almighty God?
>> We're talking in this series about
covenant living. And I believe this is
it's really the foundation of
Christianity. It's really sad that you
don't hear more people talking about
their covenant because the the the the
faith that we have in Jesus Christ is
based on our covenant with him. We
started this series last week and I'm
going to review just for a minute
talking about the scriptures uh about
this. Let's look at Ephesians chapter 2
and verse number 11. It says, "Therefore
remember that you once Gentiles in the
flesh who are called uncircumcision by
what is called the circumcision made in
the flesh by hands that at that time you
were without Christ." How many of you
are without Christ at some point in your
life? That would be all of us, right? At
some point in our life, we were without
Christ. Uh we were without Christ, being
aliens from the commonwealth of Israel
and strangers from the covenants of
promise, having no hope and without God
in this world without knowing your
covenant, without knowing Jesus, not
knowing the covenant that you had. It
says we were strangers. We were
foreigners. We didn't know anything
about this. But look what it says. We
jump down to verse number 13. It says,
"But now in Christ Jesus, you who are
once far off have been brought near by
the blood of Christ." We sing a lot
about the blood. We sing a lot about the
blood of Christ. What's the blood of
Christ mean? What's it all about? We're
going to be talking more about that this
morning. Look at verse 19. Now
therefore, you are no longer strangers
and foreigners.
>> You were, but now in Christ Jesus,
you're no longer a stranger. Say, "I'm
no longer a stranger." no longer a
stranger.
>> I'm no longer a foreigner.
>> No longer a foreigner,
>> but fellow citizens with the saints and
members of the household of God. So, we
have a class in our Bible college now.
We're launching it in the fall and we
have a class on the blood covenant. I'm
not going to go into all of the details
of that class. There's just so much to
talk about in your blood covenant. In
this series, we're really talking about
how to live in it, which that is really
the most important thing. How to take
advantage of and live in your covenant.
A covenant is the most sacred agreement
you can enter into with anybody.
>> The Bible is a book of covenants, and
covenants have been in our history since
the very beginning of time. There were
many covenants in the Bible. Matter of
fact, you could go all the way to the
Garden of Eden, and there are signs that
there was a covenant there. We don't
have any scripture on that. But we do
remember that remember Cain and Abel,
Adam and Eve's first two children.
Remember there were they were what were
they doing? They were making sacrifices
to God. And remember Cain got mad at
Abel because God accepted his sacrifice,
didn't accept his. And so he murdered
his brother.
>> But why were they sacrificing? Where did
they learn that? Where did that come
from? That looks like something that we
would see in a covenant. We see
covenants throughout scripture. We see
people entering into covenants together.
You remember uh David and Jonathan
entered a covenant together. We see a
covenant when Noah got off the ark and
God said, "I will never again flood uh
destroy this earth with water."
Remember, he put his rainbow in in the
sky. You remember this? That was a
covenant that God made. Not all
covenants are blood covenants. And all
not all covenants are the same. And so
we see covenants throughout scripture in
the Bible. You know, Job had a covenant.
Did you know that? The Bible doesn't go
into detail about Job's covenant, but
the the few things that we can see is
remember whenever Satan was trying to go
after Job, what did God tell him? You
can't take his life. Remember that. So
obviously, and Job was making sacrifices
before that. So obviously had a covenant
with God. We don't know the nature of
it. We don't know what kind of covenant
it was, but we know that it was a
lifepreserving covenant because God
said, "You'll not take his life." So,
that's one of the big problems and
challenges Christians have today is we
read the Bible and we're reading all
these things. We're reading in the book
of Job. We're reading about the children
of Israel and all the things that they
went through and we don't have a
covenant mindset. And so, we don't
understand what was going on. You cannot
try to live your life under the covenant
that Job was in. you you you can't it
doesn't fit what what we belong to a
what the Bible calls a new covenant.
>> Amen. And so we're going to look at that
today and we're going to look at this
new covenant God cut with a man by the
name of Abraham.
God cut a covenant with a man named
Abraham. Of course, we know that this
was a everlasting covenant. We know that
this was a blood covenant. We know that
this is the most sacred covenant that
you could cut with anybody. And God
entered into a covenant with man. Now,
let me just go ahead and tell you
something. God is really smart.
>> If you hadn't figured that out yet,
you'll realize the more you learn about
his word, you're like, God is like
beyond brilliant, right? Like he he's
working 10, 12, hundred things right
here when he's cutting a covenant with
Abraham. There's a lot of things that
he's working right now. He enters into
this covenant with Abraham. Here's the
problem.
The problem is that God is perfect.
God's word is perfect. His law is
perfect. And so God is perfect. And when
God states what he's going to do in his
covenant, he's going to do it. When God
says something, he's going to do it.
Look at this scripture in Psalms 89:34.
My covenant I will not break.
Is God going to break his covenant? My
covenant I will not break nor alter the
word that has come out of my lips. So in
other words, if God promised you
something in this covenant, he gonna do
it.
>> He's going to do it. You can take him at
his word.
>> If you said it, I'll believe it.
>> Did we just sing that?
If he said it, I'll believe it. But you
do you realize how many people do not
believe God when he says something. And
Christians seem to struggle when God
tells us something. When he makes us the
promise, we're like, I don't know if I
can believe that or not. Well, think
about this. The common contract that you
have today is based off of a covenant,
right? Except it's not in blood. You
sign your name these days in our
culture. You just sign your name and
say, "Yeah, that was me and I I signed
my name." You go to You go to buy a
house, you sign all this paperwork and
you enter into a contractual agreement
to buy this house. Or you go to a car
dealership to buy a car and you sign the
paper and you enter into a contract to
to buy this car and nobody's ever
shocked when they bring you the car.
Have you ever been shocked? You go into
a car dealership to buy a car and then
you're like, "Boy, I just hope they
bring that car around. I hope I get to
have this car. I just don't, man. I just
I know I just signed a paperwork, but
I'm just not sure." You got more faith
in a silly little contract to buy a car
than we do in the word of God.
>> You believe the salesman,
>> a car salesman,
and we know they don't always tell us
the truth. and you fully have full
confidence that they are going to give
you the car that you just signed for.
>> Am I right about it?
>> We We do this all the time in our
culture and and we don't think anything
about it. It It just happens, right? You
go to this McDonald's to buy you a
cheeseburger and you pay for that
cheeseburger first and you're you're not
even worried if they're going to bring
it to you or not. You're not even
worried. Well, you might need to be
worried, but no, you shouldn't be
worried about that.
You're not you you just you just expect
because they said they're going to bring
you a cheeseburger. I paid for it. So,
it's coming. The French fries are
coming. I just go sit down and relax and
drink my get my little Coke ready and
and you're just relaxing with your
family and talking and not even worried
about it because you know it's coming
because you got a promise, right? And
and we have more confidence in that than
we do God's word.
>> And God's the one that said, "My
covenant I will not break." So if God
says something in his covenant when he
stated what he will do in his covenant,
he will absolutely do that.
>> Every time. I said every time. And he
will not deviate from that. He will
always do what his word says.
>> Now some people misquote God a little
bit or say things about God that are not
true. And they'll say something like
this. God can do anything he wants. He's
God. No, he can't.
I said, "No, he can't."
>> You say, "Pastor, that sounds wrong.
That sounds so unreligious." I know.
>> But God can't just do whatever he wants.
He's going to do what he promised.
>> Do you see the difference? He's going to
do what he said he's going to do. It
does. He He He follows his word. So, if
he said it, he's going to do it. Yeah,
>> you can take him at his word. Amen. Why?
Because we are in a covenant with God
>> and he said, "My covenant I will not
break." But here's the problem. When he
entered into a covenant with Abraham, we
know we're not perfect.
>> None of us are perfect. We all have
flaws. And he entered into a covenant
agreement with a man who was fallible. A
man who was going to make mistakes. a
man who was going to break the covenant
and every generation after him was going
to break the covenant. There's a problem
here, right? God's not going to break
the covenant. He said, "I'm not going to
break my if I said it, I'm going to do
it." And God is perfect and he's all
powerful and all. And he can do that.
He's going to hold up his end. But by
entering into a covenant with Abraham,
God put provisions in place ahead of
time so that we could live in our
covenant.
Let's read about it. We're going to read
some scripture today that most people
just read over or when you read it, you
don't know anything about it because
it's all about your covenant. But let's
read here what God did, the provision he
put in place so that man wouldn't have
to die. Because violating the covenant,
you know, there was a blessing
associated with following God's law and
then there was cursings associated with
it leading up to death. And there was
many things that that that that led to
death. If you broke the covenant, you
deserve to die.
And and people read these kind of things
in the Old Testament. They're like,
"Man, God's so harsh. God's so mean. God
is not mean at all.
>> If you didn't make your car payment and
they came repossessed it, you wouldn't
say, "Well, they're so mean.
You entered into a contract to pay for
that car, you didn't pay for it for
three months, so they showed up at your
door and said, "Give me the car." It
wasn't personal. It wasn't because they
didn't like you. It's because you
violated the contract.
And that's what you're seeing throughout
the Old Testament. You're seeing the
children of Israel following the Lord.
Then they violated the covenant. bad
things began to happen. But God put
provisions in place for that. Let's read
about it. Leviticus chapter 16 and verse
5.
It says, "And he shall take from the
congregation of the children of Israel
two kinds of the goats as a sin offering
and one ram as a burnt offering. Aaron,
who was the high priest, by the way,
Aaron shall offer the bull as a sin
offering, which is for himself, and make
atonement. Say, atonement.
>> Is the big Bible word right here.
Atonement. Make atonement for himself
and for his house. He shall take two
goats and present them before the Lord
at the door of the tabernacle of
meeting. Then Aaron shall cast lots for
the two goats. One lot for the Lord and
the other lot for the scapegoat.
You ever hear that term before?
Scapegoat. Wonder where it comes from.
Comes from the Bible. It comes from
covenant language. Can you just It's
just shocking to me how much covenant
language and covenant practice are in
our culture and nobody knows. Have you
ever used the term scapegoat? So it says
here that there's going to be a
scapegoat. What happens to the scapegoat
here and the other escape goat? And
Aaron shall bring the goat on which the
Lord's lot fell and offer it as a sin
offering. But the goat on which the lot
fell to be the scapegoat shall be
presented alive before the Lord to make
atonement upon it and to let it go as
the scapegoat into the wilderness. Well,
we know what a scapegoat is, right? The
scapegoat's the one that takes the
blame. And so there were two goats that
they would bring. And they would bring a
bull. Aaron would bring a bull. And this
was happening once a year. This is known
as the day of atonement. And this day of
atonement, what Aaron, the high priest,
was supposed to do is sacrifice the
bull. Sacrifice one of the goats as an
offering. It's a sin offering to the
Lord. The other one would be the
scapegoat. And what Aaron would do is he
would pronounce the sins of Israel over
the scapegoat and then send the
scapegoat away. Does that sound familiar
to anybody? Anything you know about the
New Testament? All of your sin was put
on Jesus.
>> Jesus was your scapegoat.
>> Amen.
>> And so this would happen throughout
scripture. Now look at this verse number
16. So he shall make atonement. There it
is again. Atonement for the holy place
because of the uncleanliness of the
children of Israel and because of their
transgressions, for all their sins. So
he shall do for the tabernacle of
meeting which remains among them in the
midst of their uncleanness. There shall
be no man in the tabernacle of meeting
when he goes into it and makes atonement
in the holy place until he comes out
that he may make atonement for himself
and for his household and for all the
assembly of Israel. And he shall go out
to the altar that is before the Lord and
make atonement for it, and shall take
some of the blood of the bull and some
of the blood of the goat. These are the
ones that were sacrificed. And put it on
the horns of the altar all around. And
he shall sprinkle some of the blood on
it with the finger seven times. Cleanse
it, consecrate it from the uncleanness
of the children of Israel. So this is
the day of atonement. God gave specific
instructions to them. Specific
instructions. Why? Because he knew that
man was going to violate the covenant.
So entering into a covenant with man,
man's going to have to die. But God put
provisions in place so we didn't have to
die. He'll take an animal being
sacrificed in ourstead. and we'll put
we'll put the sins of the people on the
scapegoat and we'll sacrifice the blood
of an animal to atone for the sins of
the people. You know what this is? This
is like kicking the can down the road.
You know that expression, I'm just
kicking the can down the road. This is
this is not dealing with the issue
immediately, not dealing with this sin
issue, but covering it. To atone for
means to cover. It means to cover. And
so the sin would be covered by the blood
of these animals and the sins. And this
would happen on the day of atonement.
Once per year, the high priest would go
in and do this and sprinkle the blood.
He would go into the holy of holies in
the temple of God and sprinkle this
blood. And God gave him specific
instructions about it. Well, if you go
read all of Leviticus, you'll see that
there were daily sacrifices that had to
be made. There were weekly sacrifices
that had to be made. There were monthly
sacrifices and there were special days
where they sacrificed and then there was
the day of atonement. Day after day
after day sacrifice I mean I I did the
math on this over,200 animals a year
dying
being sacrificed over 1,200 a year
because of all of the sin. So day after
day after day they were reminded that
they were sinful. They were reminded
that they had to have this animal
sacrificed in mystead because I have not
lived up to God's standard. I have not
followed God's covenant. Day after day
after day, there was the reminder of
sin. But God put this provision in place
so man doesn't have to die. Yet.
I said yet.
>> We're kicking the can down the road
here. And so we're kicking the can down
the road. Kicking the can down the road.
And this did not do away with the sin.
It was simply covering. Atonement means
to cover. Let me tell you something. The
blood of Jesus does not atone for your
sins.
>> It doesn't sound like that's a good
religious saying, but it's true. Because
God Jesus blood did not cover your sin.
He washed your sin away.
>> Amen.
>> So this is what God did in his covenant
with Abraham.
so that we wouldn't have to die. So that
Abraham wouldn't have to die. His kids
wouldn't have to die. So when they broke
the covenant, there were provisions in
place. Here's what I want you to see.
God was lenient on their side of the
covenant. He wasn't on his.
Oh, come on, somebody.
It wasn't like God said, "Okay, this is
what we're gonna do." When you brought
said, "Okay, this is what we're gonna
do. when you break the covenant, you can
do all these sacrifices and this will
atone for the sins and we'll just kick
the can down the road and we're not
going to personally hold you accountable
for that sin. We're going to put it on
the goat. We're going to sacrifice the
bull. And he put all this in place so
that he would be lenient on them so it
wouldn't cost them their life. God
didn't do that for himself. He said, "My
covenant I will not break. I will not
violate what I said."
If God were to do that, the whole
universe should be ripped apart because
the Bible says that his word is holding
it all together right now. If he
violated his covenant, if he violated
his word, nothing would exist anymore.
So God was lenient on our side of the
covenant. He's not on his. You can in
fact take him at his word. Amen.
>> He will not violate his covenant.
>> When he promises you something in the
word of God, can you believe it? I don't
know, pastor. I just can't seem to
believe this. I can't seem I just can't
seem to go there. Do you not know you
have a covenant with God?
>> Do you not know that God will not
violate his covenant? And if he said it,
he's going to do it.
>> You're just supposed to believe it.
Well, how come I don't see these things
in my life?
because we haven't believed it.
>> Because we don't believe his word,
because we don't believe his promises.
We don't believe in his covenant.
>> Amen. So, he put this provision in place
like kicking the can down the road like
this sin issue. Man's blood would not be
shed for this. He entered into this
covenant and man should have died a long
time ago. But this provision was put in
place, these animal sacrifices so that
man did not have to pay the punishment
for that sin. But look at what happened
here in Hebrews chapter 8 verse number
one. You only can kick the can down the
roads for so long. It's like kind of
like borrowing money to pay for money
you borrowed, right? You borrow money
and then you borrow money to pay for
that. Then you borrow money to pay that
one off. Then you borrow money and you
can only do that for so long. And
eventually someone's going to have to
pay, right? You can't just keep
borrowing and borrowing and borrowing to
pay off the other debt. At some point
the debt's going to have to be paid. And
so at some point this debt was going to
have to be paid.
At some point man would have to pay for
violating the covenant.
Anybody know what happened with the man
who had to pay for that? It was Jesus.
So, we're gonna get some inside scoop
now into what Jesus did. Most Christians
only believe Jesus came to the earth,
died on the cross for their sins, okay?
And we're get to go to heaven. That's
about as far as they go. But Hebrews is
an amazing book of the Bible because
Hebrews gives us the inside scoop on
what Jesus actually did. Look at verse
number one, Hebrews 8.
Now this um this is the main point of
the things we are saying. We have such a
high priest who is seated at the right
hand of the throne of the ma in the
majesty in the heavens. Who is that?
That's Jesus.
Jesus is your high priest.
Jesus is your high priest under our new
covenant. Jesus is our high priest. Look
at verse number two. a minister of the
sanctuary and of the true tabernacle
which the Lord erected and not a man.
For every high priest is appointed to
offer both gifts and sacrifices.
Therefore, it is necessary that this one
also have something to offer. For if if
he were on earth, that tells you he's
not on the earth right now. If he were
on the earth, he would not be a priest
since there are priests who offer the
gifts according to the law, who serve
the copy and shadow of the heavenly
things.
We're talking about a temple in heaven.
We're talking about Jesus in heaven
being your high priest and my high
priest. Why do you think God was so
specific when he told them how to build
the temple? You know, you read these
things in the Bible and you're just
like, "This is just boring. I just don't
know why we go in all these details of
why we got to be." Have you read through
this? Like he when he told him to build
the temple, he was so specific. It was
down to every last little detail. He
called it out and measured this, build
it this size. What was he doing? He was
creating, he was having them build on
the earth an exact replica of the temple
that's in heaven.
And it's very clear from scripture.
We'll we'll continue to see this.
Who serve as a copy and a shadow of the
heavenly things as Moses was divinely
instructed when he was about to make the
tabernacle. For he said, "See that you
make all things according to the pattern
shown you on the mountain."
This is why he gave him the pattern
because you're going to build a temple
on the earth exactly like the one up
here. Now, let's look what he says in
verse number uh skip over to Hebrews
9:6.
Now, when these things had thus uh
prepared, the priest always went into
the first part of the tabernacle
performing the services, but into the
second part the high priest went alone
once a year.
This is talking exactly about the day of
atonement once a year when the high
priest would go into the holy of holies.
We're we're reading about it here in the
New Testament right here in the book of
Hebrews. We're reading about this moment
we read about in Leviticus where the
high priest would go in. He would he
would cast the lot and one goat would be
the scapegoat. The other one would be
slaughtered, bull be slaughtered, and he
would sprinkle the blood the blood over
and and it would atone for the sins of
the people. What we just read about he's
talking about right here.
And he said the high priest went alone
once a year, not without blood. He had
to go in there with blood, not without
blood, which offered for himself and for
the people sins committed in ignorance.
The Holy Spirit indicating this that the
way into the holiest of all was not yet
made manifest while the first tabernacle
was still standing.
Now let's look at verse 11.
But Christ say Christ.
>> Christ.
>> Christ came as what?
>> High priest. Remember we said he is your
high priest. As high priest of the good
things to come with the greater and more
perfect tabernacle not made with hands.
Which one we talking about? We're not
talking about the one on the earth.
We're talking about the heavenly
tabernacle.
that is not of this creation. Not listen
to me now. Oh, this is going to set some
of you free. Not with the blood of goats
and calves,
>> but with his own blood.
>> With his own blood, he entered into the
most holy place once and for all.
>> Once and for all. What does that mean?
That means this doesn't have to happen
once a year. That means this doesn't
have to happen every day, every week,
every month on the Jewish festival days
and in the day of atonement. This this
means that this is once and for all,
>> once and for all with his own blood,
having obtained eternal redemption.
For if the blood of bulls and goats, and
the ashes of a hepher, sprinkling the
unclean, sanctifies for the purifying of
the flesh, how much more,
how much more shall the blood of Christ,
who through the eternal spirit offered
himself without spot to God, cleanse
your conscience from dead works to serve
a living God.
>> What What are we seeing here? What is
this? This is what we're seeing is Jesus
after he died on the cross and he
ascended into heaven, he brought his
blood and he entered into the holy of
holies, the most holy place in the
tabernacle of heaven and he did the
exact same sacrifice
that Aaron the priest, the high priest
would do, except he did it with his own
blood. And the blood of a goat. This was
much more powerful than the blood of a
goat or a bull because this blood did
not atone for the sins. It was washing
the sins away.
>> That's why it says once and for all.
>> Once and for all. Amen.
>> What does this mean to us? This means
that Jesus is not going daily in the
temple and offering his blood.
>> He's not doing this every day. He's not
doing this every week. Some people teach
that. They say, "Well, Jesus has got to
go in because I sin. Tomorrow, Jesus has
got to go back in." No, he did it once
and for all. Say, "Once and for all."
>> Once and for all.
>> He did it once and for all.
>> And he did it for every single person
that would ever live on planet Earth.
Amen.
>> What does this mean for us?
What does this mean for us now? How do
we how do we take advantage of this in
our covenant now? How does this affect
the way we live? Here's the thing I want
to tell you.
You and I don't have to live with a sin
conscience.
>> You and I don't have to live like they
did under the old covenant.
>> Daily reminded of you're a failure,
reminded of your sin, reminded of how
many times you screwed up and we've got
to do sacrifice after. And it was a
daily reminder, a weekly reminder, a
yearly reminder. No longer do you have
to live that way.
>> Do you realize that Christians all over
the planet have fallen for the devil's
lies and trap and every day they wake up
feeling condemned. They feel like
they're under condemnation. They feel
like, "Oh, why? Because they've sinned.
Because they messed up. Oh, I messed up
again. Oh, I messed up again and again
and again." And the devil's like, "Yeah,
you dirty, rotten sinner. You're nothing
but a sinner." And people have said it.
I'm just an old sinner. No, you're not.
>> I said, "No, you're not."
>> Because the blood of Jesus has done
once. Say once and for all.
>> Oh, you're not you're not sure now
because we're talking about my sin now.
>> See, here's here's the problem.
Christians have had bad teaching on this
and they've been taught that every time
you sin now Jesus has got to go do
something for you.
>> You've got to repent of it. Jesus got to
sprinkle the blood again. Got to go into
the Holy of Holies. Or they don't even
know what it means. They just believe
that's the way it is. I've got to I've
got to confess my sin. Jesus has got to
once again forgive me of my sins and all
these kind of things. And then and then
and and this is why listen to me now.
This is why the erroneous teaching that
if someone commits suicide, they're
going to hell. That's where it comes
from.
>> And I just felt impressed of the spirit
to tell you today that that's not true.
>> The reason they teach that is because
if someone commits suicide, the very
last act on this earth was to kill
somebody themselves.
And they didn't have time to repent,
>> right? Didn't have time to repent. So,
you must be going to hell.
>> Is that what we're seeing from
scripture?
>> That that's where that teaching comes
from.
>> Well, it's not just suicide. What if you
yelled at your wife and then stepped out
in front of a car and got run over by a
car?
What if you sinned, but it wasn't as
bad, right? We categorize these things,
but it wasn't that bad. But what if, but
what if your little white lie or your
little sin happened right before you
die? And you know how many people sin
before they die
>> or they're sinning when they die.
>> This happens all the time.
>> It's not just people who are committing
suicide. It happens all the time. So,
well, pastor, how can I go to heaven if
if I've committed sin and I haven't
asked forgiveness for it? Because the
blood of Jesus
>> has already paid the price for your sin
once and for all. Say, "Once and for
all."
>> And for all.
>> Once and for all. What does that mean?
He doesn't have to do it again.
>> Once and for all. Amen.
>> We're going to see some more scripture
about this.
Hebrews 10, chapter 10. I'm fired up
>> You need to know how to live in your
covenant. And you need to stop listening
to the lies of the devil bringing
condemnation on you because you screw
up.
God had a plan. Oh, God is so good.
>> Don't be Don't be talking bad about my
God
>> saying how he wants you sick. He wants
you broke. He wants you depressed. He
planned this a long time ago.
>> He He put these sacrifices in place, the
whole priesthood and all of this so man
wouldn't be punished for their sin. And
then he sent Jesus to pay the price for
your sin so you wouldn't have to pay it.
So the price would be paid. Don't tell
me God is bad.
>> He's a good God.
>> He loves you.
>> I mean, he could have just been like,
"You know what? I'm tired of them.
Thump,
>> that's all of us.
>> Aren't you glad you're not God or I'm
not God? They just keep sinning. Get rid
of them.
Our patience have been gone, right? God
is so merciful. His mercy, the Bible
says,
>> endures
>> forever.
>> He's so merciful. He's so loving and
kind. He put no provision in place if he
screwed up. But for us, he got all these
provisions in place. And then he sent
Jesus. So he knew this man will not
violate the covenant.
>> And he knew that this man would live a
perfect sinless life. And then they
turned around and killed him for it.
fell right into God's master plan trap.
The Bible says that that that the devil
would have known what this was, but he's
too stupid.
>> God's he's like 10, 15, 150 steps ahead
of him.
>> And then it's only after the fact he was
like, "Maybe we shouldn't have killed
Jesus because now the blood of Jesus has
paid for all of these people's sins.
>> Now I'm going to have to lie."
>> And he's okay with that. And how many
people do you know living living this
way under the condemnation of sin? The
devil's like, "Yeah, look at you. Yeah,
you can't do anything for God. Look at
your sin. Look at how many times you
messed up." Even after you're a
Christian, look how many times you
messed up. What kind of Christian are
you?
The Bible says once and for all. Say
once and for all.
>> Once and for all.
>> I'll read this. Hebrews 10:10. Listen to
this. But that the but that will I'm
sorry. By that will, I get so stirred
up. I can't even read it. By that will,
we have been sanctified through the
offering of the body of Jesus Christ.
>> Once for all.
>> Oh man, here it is again. You know, when
the Bible repeats something, he's trying
to make a point. Yeah.
>> And every priest stands ministering
daily and offering repeatedly the same
sacrifices which can never say never
>> take away sins. All those sacrifices did
not take away the sin. It atoned for it.
>> There's been horrible teaching in the
church that said Jesus blood atoned for
your sin. It did not.
>> I got one amen. See, it just sounds bad,
right? You're like, I can't believe he
said that. Jesus, let's say it again.
Jesus blood did not atone for your sin.
>> It did not cover your sin. It did not
put it on a goat and send it running
away into the wilderness. It washed it
away.
>> It's gone.
>> Jesus was the scapegoat. It was put on
him and he walked into the holy of
holies with his own blood. The blood of
a man
>> and sprinkled it on the mercy seat. He's
He did the exact same thing except it
was with a man's blood. Now the price
has been paid.
>> You got to know your covenant
>> once and for all. Every priest stands
ministering daily and offering
repeatedly the same sacrifices which can
never take away sins. But this man after
he had offered one sacrifice for sins
>> forever.
[laughter]
>> Am I the only one stirred up about this
>> one sacrifice?
>> Thank God we don't have to do this every
day. Thank God I don't have if I was the
h Oh my goodness. I retired.
>> I quit. Are you kid? That was a lot of
work.
>> A lot of bulls, a lot of calves, a lot
of goats. I mean, that's just a that's
bloody
gross, right? I mean, that's just it was
just think about how much and it was a
constant constant reminder. You're still
a sinner. You're still a sinner. You're
still a sinner. You still got sin in
your life. We don't have to do that.
Why? Because just this man had offered
one sacrifice for sins forever.
>> I said forever.
>> Do I need to define this word for you
guys?
>> Forever means
>> for all time.
>> He don't have to do it again.
>> If if this was not the case, Jesus would
have to come back to the earth. He would
have to die again. And he would have to
come back to the Holy of Holies and
sprinkle more blood.
And then Jason sinned again. Here we go.
Come back Jesus and do it again. And
Jesus comes back to the earth again. The
sinless son of God dies again. Goes in
again and and day. And Jesus doesn't
have to do this every day. You need to
know what covenant you're living under.
>> You need to know that the blood of a man
was what was required.
This is what was required by the
covenant because man had sinned. Man's
blood had to be shed.
>> But God is so merciful. He sent his son.
Isn't that awesome?
>> That's amazing. It says once and for all
for the sins forever, sat down at the
right hand of God from that time waiting
till his enemies are made his foottool.
For by one offering he has perfected
forever those who are being sanctified.
one offering.
>> Man, what an offering.
>> What an offering that was by his own
blood. Now, here's the question. Every
Christian deals with every Christians uh
I shouldn't say every there's a lot of
people have no idea what we just went
through. No idea that the blood of Jesus
has washed them clean. They think it's
atonement or they think that this is
something that repeatedly has to be done
repeatedly. Repeatedly. He doesn't have
to do this all the time. He paid for
your sins, past, present, and future.
Not just yours, but every person that
would ever live.
>> Once and for all.
>> Remember, we said it multiple times.
Once and for all. Once and for all. Once
and for all. Once and for all.
>> We got to get it through our thick
skull.
>> You don't have to live
under condemnation because you sinned.
>> You don't.
>> You can if you listen to the lies of the
devil. every time you screw up, he'll
tell you that. You'll be like, "Ah." So,
what do we do? Here's here's the
problem. Here's how here's where
Christians are. Christians are like,
"Okay, pastor, I get you, but now that
I'm born again
and I sin, what now?" See, you don't
know your covenant. You don't realize
that he did it once and for all. It
wasn't just before you were born again,
all those sins. It was all of your sins
forever.
>> All of them.
>> Yeah.
>> Which leads people to think, well, okay,
that means I can sin as much as I want
>> because they're all covered under the
blood of Jesus and I can sin as much as
I want.
Can you?
>> What if you sinned a hundred times? You
still going to heaven?
>> Yes. No. I don't know. Trick question
time.
What if you sinned a thousand times?
What if you are like going to make it a
mission after I'm born again? I'm going
to sin as much as I can. See if I can
still make it.
What would that be?
We gonna make it.
Tim's like, "You're on thin ice."
[laughter]
Is it once and for all or once and for
all?
>> You You're okay with Once and for all
just a minute ago, but when I started
putting numbers on it, you're like, "I
don't know about you now, pastor. I
don't know. You just gonna keep on
sinning. You shouldn't want to sin
anymore
>> as a believer, as a Christian.
>> You shouldn't want to,
but we do. We mess up. We make mistakes,
right? What happens now? Is that is that
sin not covered under the blood of
Jesus? No. With sacrifices once and for
all, that sin's covered as well. Well,
why can't I just sin as much as I want?
Why can't Well, what we just read, let
me read it again to you.
It says, "But this man, after he had
offered one sacrifice for sin forever,
sat down at the right hand of God from
that time waiting." What's he waiting
for? He's waiting till his enemies are
made his foottool.
Drop the mic.
>> He's waiting for his enemies. And this
word foottool is a very interesting
word. When when you start digging into
what this actually means, we know what a
foottool is. My my grandmother was 4
foot six and she had a foot stool at
church and she used to sit on the front
row and uh because you know her feet
would not touch the ground. That's why
she had a foot stool. So she had this
little this little foottool here and she
would put her feet on it because they
they weren't long enough to reach the
ground. That's a foottool, right? It is,
but it has more meaning than that.
This term foottool is actually has the
meaning more of not just something you
put your feet on, but the idea of
conquest and conquering.
Like when someone would defeat an army,
they would come and they would put their
foot right on the person's neck. It was
a sign of conquest. It was a sign of
conquering them. They were now their
foottool. They put their foot right
there on their neck and just stood and
just stood there.
He's waiting till his enemies are made
his foottool. Well, who are the enemies?
Well, we know the devil's an enemy. The
Bible says death is an enemy.
There are many enemies, right? So, whose
responsibility now is it to do these
things?
Living under our new covenant, not
hindered by sin any longer? Sin should
not stop you from doing what God's
called you to do. Sin should not stop
you from being the person God's called
you to be. Now all that's been done away
with. Jesus took care of all that. Once
and for all. We said, "Yay, pastor. Once
and for all.
Once and for all." And so now all that
all those excuses are gone. You don't
have to sacrifice the day. It's all
over. But pastor, I screwed up. Shut
your mouth.
>> Your job now is to do the work of God on
the earth. Your job is to make sure his
enemies are made his foottool.
>> Your job is to take the word of God. So,
so why could I sin as much as I want?
Why do you want to? That's not our
purpose.
>> It's not our purpose.
>> And if you want to sin that much, I
would question, are you saved? Do you
love Jesus? Because the closer you get
to Jesus, the more you don't want to
sin.
>> Doesn't mean you're perfect. You still
gonna screw up. But the but the more
you're you turn your heart towards him,
you don't want to do that any longer.
I'll use this example as we close.
Angela and I took a couple to dinner one
night and and uh it was family members
long time ago. And you know when you
take someone out to dinner and you're
going to pay for the meal and it's
understood upfront, what do you not do?
You don't order everything on the menu,
right? And we took this couple out and
and they found out we were buying and
man it was the they ordered the
Admiral's Feast. It was at Red Lobster
back in the day. Admiral's Feast, which
was the most expensive thing on the
menu. And not just one Admiral's Feast,
two.
And then they ordered appetizers. And
then after it was all over, they wanted
>> Have you been there? And I'm sitting
there going, "Well, just because I'm
paying doesn't mean I wanted you to do
all that." And I really feel like that's
kind of how Jesus is.
I really feel like that's kind of the
heart behind the sin issue.
Yes, all those sins are paid for, but
he's like, "I don't want you to do that.
>> I didn't pay for all your sins so you
could just keep on sinning all you
want."
>> What do we do now? Let's read it here in
1 John chapter
uh 1 verse 8.
If we say that we have no sin, we
deceive ourselves.
>> Well, what this is saying is there's
still sin. We still have sin, right? We
still sin. But having sin in your life
does not make you a sinner.
>> Doesn't change your identity in Christ
at all.
>> You are washed clean by the blood of
Jesus. Even though you've got sin now,
there's obviously there's sin. We mess
up.
So if we say we have no sin, we deceive
ourselves. Don't get prideful and say,
"I going to sin now because of Jesus."
No, you're still messing up.
>> And the truth is not in us. If we
confess our sin, he is faithful and just
to forgive us our sins and to cleanse us
from all unrighteousness.
>> And you see that see there, pastor, you
got to confess your sins or you're not
going to be cleansed of them.
That's where they get it.
But you know what? We got to go back to
what with the basics that we've learned.
When you got born again, what part of
you got born again?
What part of you? Your spirit was born
again. The real you on the inside was
born again. Washed clean by the blood of
Jesus. And out came the old man. In came
the new man. And by the way, the Holy
Spirit came with him.
>> And now you got the spirit of God on the
inside of you as a Christian. And the
Bible says that you were sealed.
Nothing's breaking that seal.
>> So when you sin after you're born again,
it's still bad for you. I'm not saying
it's good for you. I Jesus has already
paid the price for it. The blood of
Jesus washes you clean from it in your
spirit.
But how many of you know my soul was not
born again? I had someone cut me off in
traffic yesterday.
>> I found out real quick my soul was not
born again. because I was having
thoughts of things I wanted to do to
him.
>> That wasn't godly thoughts.
>> I didn't let them come out of my mouth,
but I think I said, what did I say? I
said something. It was I mean, it wasn't
positive.
I'll just say that. I wasn't cussing or
nothing, but it was bad. I mean, it
wasn't good. My soul's not born again. I
have and I have a physical body that's
not been born again.
>> So, when we sin after we're a Christian,
you're still going to heaven. Your
salvation is not in question. If someone
were to commit suicide, their spirit is
sealed up. They're still going to
heaven.
>> If they sin before they die and they
don't confess it, they're still going to
heaven. What I'm saying is this is not a
salvation issue,
>> but it is an issue in your soul and it
is an issue in your physical body. When
you sin as a New Testament born again
Christian, you open your physical body
and your soul, your mind up to the devil
>> and you allow him to come in and do what
he wants to do. Well, think about it.
How many Christians do you know messed
up in their mind? Physical bodies are
suffering.
Learn how to live in your covenant. When
you violate the covenant, when you sin
as a New Testament Christian, what do
you do? The Bible says, "Confess your
sin." What do you do? You You agree with
God. What I did was wrong.
>> That's what a confession is. I'm in
agreement. I'm going to say what he
said. He said it's wrong. I say it's
wrong. I confess that, God, that was
wrong. Thank you for Thank you for for
paying the price for that. But when I
release that to God and acknowledge that
to God, it washes me clean. My soul, my
physical body is no longer a prey of the
enemy.
>> Oh, this explains a little bit, doesn't
it?
>> What about when we just hang on to these
things and we sin and we just hang on to
that sin? What does it do? It opens us
up to attack from the enemy. Doesn't
mean I'm not going to heaven. Doesn't
mean I'm not saved.
See, you don't have to live with a sin
conscience any longer.
You don't have to live your life daily
with this constant bombarding. Ah, I
just can't. I just can't. What you need
to do is learn how to live in your
covenant.
Learn that Jesus has paid the price once
and for all. We said for all eternity,
it says and his covenant is with us.
Well, I'm not Abraham's seed. Well, the
Bible says that those of us who have
accepted in Galatians 3, we say this all
the time, but this is covenant language.
In Galatians 3, it says because you
accepted Jesus as your savior and you're
now in Christ, you are now Abraham's
seed.
>> Seed
and hes according to the promise.
You're in the covenant. Congratulations.
>> Your sin gone.
What if I keep sinning? You better You
need to stop. You need to stop it. Quit.
You're opening yourself up to attack
from the enemy.
>> And why do you want to in the first
place? I don't know about you, I want to
live my life for the Lord. Amen.
>> Let's all bow our heads today. Thank
you, Jesus. I believe there's people
here today that you've been bombarded
with these thoughts, this condemnation
of sin because you keep messing up. You
keep messing up. But it's like
rehearsing this over and over in your
mind. The Lord wanted me to tell you
today that you do not have to live this
way any longer.
You don't have to live under that
condemnation any longer.
Those sins have been washed by the blood
once and for all. He said, "You don't
have to live that way. You don't have to
be this way. You don't have to allow the
devil to constantly bring it up." Well,
pastor, what do I do when he does? You
remind him of the blood of Jesus. You
remind him that your sins are paid for.
You remind him that you have a covenant
with almighty God. Father, in the name
of Jesus, I thank you. Thank you for
your covenant. Thank you that our sins
are forgiven. They've been washed away.
They are gone. They have been sent on
the scapegoat and they are they are
eradicated from our lives. Thank you
Lord the price has been paid once and
for all. That the blood of Jesus was
enough. And I thank you Lord that we can
now live without the sin conscience
without the constant reminders of our
failures and our flaws. But Lord we can
lean into our covenant and our covenant
promises and declare say what you say
about us. We can trust what you say and
we can lean on your word and stand on
our covenant promises. Thank you, Lord,
for setting us free from sin. Thank you,
Lord, that we don't have to be
condemned.
Thank you, Lord, that we don't have to
live that way any longer in the name of
Jesus. Amen. Amen. Thank you, Lord. If
you need prayer today, I want you to
come forward after the service. If
you've been tormented by this, I I feel
like today there's been people that have
been just so tormented by this sin
issue. It's really bothered you. And I
believe today the Lord is opening your
eyes and setting you free. Amen. Amen.
If you need prayer, come forward after
the service. We love you guys. Have a
great week this week. God bless you. And
we'll see you next Sunday.